# Seon O'Shannon

Developer | Manager



seon@eons.llc



+1 (775) 354-4343



Reno, NV



https://eons.llc

# About me –

From biotechnology to de novo AI to custom clouds to business, my breadth of experience allows me to easily cross disciplines and move ideas from theory into practice. Diving deep into how systems work and learning what I can do to improve them is one of my great joys. It doesn't matter if I have to learn a new programming language, backdoor a broken server, design hardware, build new organisms, or change whole ecosystems, I'm up for any challenge and will take any opportunity to leave this world better than I found it.

# Skills -

Leadership

C++

Python

**Cloud Architecture** 

**Embedded Systems** 

Hardware & Electrical Engineering

Linux

**Windows** 

**Android** 

**Version Control + CI/CD** 

Security

**Experiment Design & Debugging** 

(\*)[The skill scale represents confidence over perceived possible growth]

### Experience

2015-2019 Lead Software Engineer

Brain2Bot

Using C++, Qt, and novel neuroscience I designed, developed, and deployed a software platform for building brains. I wrote drivers and wired together off-the-shelf hardware to create robot pets which responded to stimuli in real time, leaned from their experience, and had their own internal emotions and goals. Later, I deployed the same software through Unreal Engine targeting both Windows and Android.

2017-2021 Research Associate

Zeaka

I worked on the majority of a genetic engineering pipeline as well as managed other personnel, equipment, greenhouses, labs, and reagents. Using both Excel and Python, I wrote and mathematically verified software for automating the digestion of experimental data, enabling faster time-to-results across numerous studies. For collaboration with our global team, I built and hosted data servers for research results.

2020-now Founder & CEO

eons LL0

With my team, I manage both customer and vendor relations, planning and implementation of new technologies, and training of employees. I also maintain & secure a globally distributed, productiongrade Kubernetes system which my clients rely on.

2021-now Solutions Architect

**AOE Greens** 

With AOE Greens, I designed and built fully integrated, custom IoT solutions. The CEO and I collaborated on hardware design, wired power, control, and actuation circuits for a hydroponic system, and trained our employees on how to use the systems we built. I provided custom software and cloud infrastructure for controlling our hardware through a secure web interface.

#### **Education**

2013-2017

**B.S. Biochemistry & Molecular Biology**Thesis: "Overexpression of DGAT1 and Modified Cysteine Soy

Oleosin Increases Oil Content in the Green Tissue of *Arabidopsis thaliana*", also earned a minor in mathematics.

GPA: 3.402

## Achievements

2014 Eagle Scout

Boy Scouts of America

Eagle scout project was painting a map of the United States at Virginia

Palmer Elementary School.

2016 Secretary & Director

Reno Video Game Symphony

Designed & implemented a constitution for the Reno Video Game

Symphony and made the organization 501(c)(3) nonprofit.

### Projects by Release Date

2020 **Web Infrastructure** https://web.infrastructure.tech/architecture/

Globally distributed Kubernetes cluster & auto-managed WordPress.

2021 Eons Basic Build System https://github.com/eons-dev/bin\_ebbs

Extensible build system for any language and process, all in Python.

in progress Develop Biology

https://develop.bio

Open source, backwards compatible, recursive hypergraph with re-

flection and a frontend as my own programming language.

# Latest

Get the latest version of this resume at https://github.com/eons44/doc\_resume References are available upon request (they will not be stored on the public repo).